<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2019-04-25T07:00:22+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Psychedelic Symphony</title><subtitle>Combining music, color, and VR in a new and exciting way</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Week 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/19/Week-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 2" /><published>2019-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/19/Week-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/19/Week-2/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-everyone-did&quot;&gt;What Everyone Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, as a collective team we further developed our idea for creating a Psychedlelic Symphony experience in VR by creating a rough outline of gameplay, setting, possible interactions, and possible visual designs.
We gathered these ideas into a narrative and explanation for Tuesday’s pitch to the class, accompanied by a colorful slide deck proposing our awesome project.
On Thursday, we all contributed to writing up our PRD, established milestones for the rest of the quarter, and set up initial individual roles within the team to address different project aspects. All of this was listed in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/122QkSjIWo0ORuT68aMuipd6LAAxZwBrRgFNYhNKyHvQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;PRD&lt;/a&gt;, along with the specific assets we already picked out. 
AJ found a simple, yet elegant concert hall as the setting for our game, while Hannah and Ben explored additional assets and discussed game mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-update&quot;&gt;Code Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team members continued to individually work on and looked at Unity/Steam tutorials to prepare for future project work. 
PJ set up the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UWRealityLab/vrcapstone19sp-team7/tree/master/PhantasiaConductor&quot;&gt;basic overall repo&lt;/a&gt; for the project and began work on the first puzzle implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;idea-update&quot;&gt;Idea Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of last week, we decided on creating an interactive, rich symphony experience, similar to Fantasia 2000, but with minigame puzzles to explore rhythms and melodies in the various orchestral sections of a song.
The project is currently titled “Psychedelic Symphony”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-for-next-week&quot;&gt;Plan for Next Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flesh out details on the mechanics, structure, and other features of the puzzles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select a song and start working on syncing audio snippets to objects/motions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Begin coding the first puzzle for the rhythm section&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up basic environment and layout with boxes to mark objects to interact with&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick out initial basic assets and explore the physics effects on shapes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blocking-issues&quot;&gt;Blocking Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determining the right song and brainstorming puzzles to work in the context of the melody and rhythm will require much creativity.
It is currently unknown how difficult it will be to coordinate the audio, motions/interactions, and visuals at the minimal/most basic level, but it could require quite a bit of debugging and coding directed at precision of timing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What Everyone Did This week, as a collective team we further developed our idea for creating a Psychedlelic Symphony experience in VR by creating a rough outline of gameplay, setting, possible interactions, and possible visual designs. We gathered these ideas into a narrative and explanation for Tuesday’s pitch to the class, accompanied by a colorful slide deck proposing our awesome project. On Thursday, we all contributed to writing up our PRD, established milestones for the rest of the quarter, and set up initial individual roles within the team to address different project aspects. All of this was listed in the PRD, along with the specific assets we already picked out. AJ found a simple, yet elegant concert hall as the setting for our game, while Hannah and Ben explored additional assets and discussed game mechanics. Code Update Team members continued to individually work on and looked at Unity/Steam tutorials to prepare for future project work. PJ set up the basic overall repo for the project and began work on the first puzzle implementation. Idea Update At the end of last week, we decided on creating an interactive, rich symphony experience, similar to Fantasia 2000, but with minigame puzzles to explore rhythms and melodies in the various orchestral sections of a song. The project is currently titled “Psychedelic Symphony” Plan for Next Week Flesh out details on the mechanics, structure, and other features of the puzzles Select a song and start working on syncing audio snippets to objects/motions Begin coding the first puzzle for the rhythm section Set up basic environment and layout with boxes to mark objects to interact with Pick out initial basic assets and explore the physics effects on shapes Blocking Issues Determining the right song and brainstorming puzzles to work in the context of the melody and rhythm will require much creativity. It is currently unknown how difficult it will be to coordinate the audio, motions/interactions, and visuals at the minimal/most basic level, but it could require quite a bit of debugging and coding directed at precision of timing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/12/Week-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1" /><published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/12/Week-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/12/Week-1/">&lt;p&gt;This was our brainstorming week so most of our time was spent coming up with ideas and figuring out our project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-everyone-did&quot;&gt;What Everyone Did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, we engaged in lengthly brainstorming sessions to decide on a project idea that would let us explore the richness of VR capabilities in novel ways. After setting up a website and several collaborative tools, including a Slack channel and git branch for our webpage, we put together a polished project proposal included here (NOTE PUT PROJECT PROPOSAL HERE/IN POST SOMEWHERE)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-update&quot;&gt;Code Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team members individually worked on and looked at Unity/Steam tutorials to prepare for future project work. No project coding has been done as of yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;idea-update&quot;&gt;Idea Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided on creating an interactive puzzle game that leverages the unique space of VR to engage and entertain users while also promoting critical and creative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-for-next-week&quot;&gt;Plan for Next Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flesh out details on the mechanics, structure, and other features of the puzzles and overall game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blocking-issues&quot;&gt;Blocking Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working out the finer elements of what our puzzles will look like and how to implement them will be an interesting challenge this coming week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This was our brainstorming week so most of our time was spent coming up with ideas and figuring out our project. What Everyone Did This week, we engaged in lengthly brainstorming sessions to decide on a project idea that would let us explore the richness of VR capabilities in novel ways. After setting up a website and several collaborative tools, including a Slack channel and git branch for our webpage, we put together a polished project proposal included here (NOTE PUT PROJECT PROPOSAL HERE/IN POST SOMEWHERE) Code Update Team members individually worked on and looked at Unity/Steam tutorials to prepare for future project work. No project coding has been done as of yet. Idea Update We decided on creating an interactive puzzle game that leverages the unique space of VR to engage and entertain users while also promoting critical and creative thinking. Plan for Next Week Flesh out details on the mechanics, structure, and other features of the puzzles and overall game. Blocking Issues Working out the finer elements of what our puzzles will look like and how to implement them will be an interesting challenge this coming week.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /></entry></feed>